# Oleksandr Ratushnyi

Front-end engineer

Kremenchuk, Ukraine T: +380679340776 E: alexander.ratushnyi@gmail.com
G: https://github.com/a1exalexander

L: alexander-ratushnyi

W: https://sashkoratushnyi.com

### **Summary**

A skilled Front-end Developer from Ukraine with over 6 years of experience, I have worked with a wide range of technologies, with a preference for React + TypeScript. Specialized in system design, web development, test covering, team management, development processes, and development delivery, I have successfully developed and managed over 15 projects from inception to production, with more than 7 handled independently. Additionally, I have experience in teaching and creating courses in front-end development.

# **Technologies**

Javascript, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, React, Node.js, Strapi CMS, Next.js, Vue, Nuxt, NestJS, Fastify, SQL, PostgreSQL, Prisma, Redis, Remix, Redux, MobX, MVC, DDD, CA, FSD, OOP, SDLC

# **Professional Experience**

#### **Merge**

(2018 - Present) Full-stack Developer / CTO / Co-founder

Engaged in the development of web applications primarily in the fintech and SaaS sectors. Responsibilities included managing in-house developers, setting up the company's processes, hiring, and mentoring of developers. Key projects involved developing innovative financial technology solutions and scalable SaaS platforms.

#### **Merge Academy**

(2022 - 2023) Course Author / Teacher

I created a front-end development course program and started teaching it, developed a website for the academy and helped with setting up automation of course processes.

#### **WiseAlpha**

(2020) Front-end Developer

Trading and Technology for the Corporate Bond Market. Developed new features on the old and good Backbone.

#### **Beetroot Academy**

(2019 - 2021) Teacher

Taught a course on front-end development and successfully released two groups of students.

## **Freelance**

(2017 - 2021) Front-end Developer

Part-time freelance role involving diverse projects, showcasing adaptability and skill in various front-end technologies.

## **Education**

(2014) Kharkiv National University of Internal Affairs - Hold a Bachelor's Degree in Jurisprudence (2017) Graduated from the National Academy of Internal Affairs. Hold a Master's Degree in Jurisprudence

### Other

**Languages**: English (Advanced), Ukrainian (Native) **Hobbies**: Photography, Photo Retouching, Pizza Cooking